《谍影重重》
真是一团乱
What a mess.
你以前从来没有看过死人吗?
You've never seen a dead man before?
拿张毯子盖着他 把他盖起来
Put a blanket on him. Cover him.
就来
I'm coming.
小心
Be careful.
等一下 我马上到 给他盖上
One minute. I'll be right there. Cover him.
苏黎世戈曼萨银行 000-7-17-12-0-14-26
000-7-17-12-0-14-26 Gemeinschaft Bank Zurich
你他妈的对我做了什么?
What the hell are you doing to me?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
妈的! 我在哪儿?
Goddamn it! Where am I?
一艘渔船! 你当时在水里
A boat! A fishing boat. You were in the water.
被捞上船的
We pulled you out.
什么水里?
What water?
你中弹了 看见了吗? 这是子弹
You were shot. See? There are the bullets.
听好 有个银行帐号 为什么它在你的屁股里面?
Look, there is a number for a bank. Why was it in your hip?
我的屁股?
My hip?
- 为什么在你的屁股里面? - 我的屁股
- Why was it in your hip? - My hip.
对 在你屁股皮肤下面
Yeah, in your hip under the skin.
天啊
Oh, God.
- 你要把我怎样? - 你需要休息 等等
- What are you doing with me? - You need to rest.
请躺下
Please. Lie down.
我没有恶意 我是你的朋友
I'm a friend. I'm your friend.
我叫姜卡洛
My name is Giancarlo.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你叫什么?
What's your name?
我不知道
I don't know.
- 噢 天哪 - 躺下
- Oh, God. - Lie down.
弗吉尼亚州 兰利 中央情报局总部
CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY LANGLEY, VIRGINIA
长官 已得到确认 任务失败了
It's been confirmed, sir. Mission failed.
你知道我是谁吗?
Do you know who I am?
我不知道我是谁
I do not know who I am.
告诉我 我是谁
Tell me who I am.
如果知道我是谁...
If you know who I am...
就请不要胡闹了...
Please stop messing around...
赶快告诉我
...and tell me.
想吃的话就请过来
If you want to eat, get in there.
从这些海图来看 我可能去过离海岸更近的地方
Based on these charts, I think I may have been closer to the coast.
这是什么? 你系的这些结?
What is this? You tie these knots?
- 开始恢复记忆了? - 不 还没有
- So, it starts to come back? - No, it doesn't.
这绳结没什么特别 我只是打个结
The knot's like everything else. I found the rope and I did it.
就像我能阅读
Same way I can read.
我能写字 做算术 煮咖啡
I can write. I can add, subtract. I can make coffee.
- 洗扑克牌 摆棋盘 - 你的记忆肯定能恢复
- I can shuffle cards, play chess. - Yes, it will come back.
不 恢复不了 真见鬼! 问题就出在这!
No, it's not coming back, goddamn it! That's the point!
我一直在这儿查看这些...鬼东西!
I'm down here looking through this, all this shit!
我已在这呆了两星期
For two weeks I'm down here.
这不顶用 我甚至不知道要查找什么
It's not working. I don't even know what to look for.
你需要休息 记忆会恢复的
You need to rest. It will come back.
要不恢复怎么办?
What if it doesn't come back?
明天就到港口了 我却连名字都没有
We get in there tomorrow, I don't even have a name.
这不多 但应该够你去瑞士了
It's not much, but it should get you to Switzerland.
谢谢
Thank you.
不认识这些标识吗?
Can't you read the signs?
站起来...快点 马上
On your feet...let's go...right now.
公园关门了 不许在公园过夜
The park is cIosed. There's no sleeping in the park.
好的
All right.
看一下你的证件
Let's see some identification.
我没...
No, I don't...
快拿证件
Come on...your papers.
什么证件也没有 我失去...
I don't have any papers. I lost my....
我失去它们了...我的证件 都丢了
I've lost them...my papers...they are lost.
好吧 跟我们走 举起手来
Ok...let's go...put your hands up.
我只想睡...
...I just need to sleep...
这些人威胁我的家人 我的孩子
These people have threatened my family. My babies.
所以听好了 一旦证据齐全...
So I'm telling you, when the evidence is clear...
我就有好戏让大家看
...I will have a nice story for you to read about.
还有我那边的朋友 你们会看到好戏的
And all my friends out there, you will read about yourselves.
因为在我变得理智后...
If you want to play this game...
你们若还想玩这场游戏 我就演给你们看
...after I have been reasonable, I will show you.
这是尼瓦纳·翁博希前天在巴黎的讲话
That's Nykwana Wombosi speaking in Paris the day before yesterday.
他掌权前就是个刺头 执政时则是个麻烦
He was an irritation before he took power, a probIem...
流亡后已成为我们的灾难
...when he was in power, and he's been a disaster for us in exile.
他在写书 讲中情局在非洲的行动
He's writing a book about the Agency's history in Africa.
他要点特工的名
He's going to name names.
这简直是敲诈 他在强求中情局的援助
It's basically a shaedown. He's demanding the Agency's help.
他想让我们在六个月内扶他重新上台 否则就等着瞧
He wants us to put him back in power in six months, or else.
我会把这次采访的磁带给需要者
This interview, and I'll make the tape availabIe to whoever wants it...
他在采访时还称自己刚躲过暗杀企图
...he goes on to claim that he's just survived an assassination attempt.
他说是我们干的 称自己有证据
He says it's us. He says he's got proof.
局长想知道这一指控...
The Director wants to know if there's any truth...
可有真实之处
...in this accusation.
我已向他保证我的高级幕僚中没人会这么鲁莽
I've already assured him there's nobody that recless on my senior staff.
我想起了我们以前的一次谈话
I was recalling a conversation we had some time ago.
关于"踩石"行动
Taling about Treadstone.
我似乎记得谈话中提到过翁博希的名字
I seem to remember Wombosi's name might have come up.
我不敢肯定我们谈了些什么
I'm not sure what we're talking about.
有人试图把他干掉
Someone tried to take him out.
但却失手了
Tried and failed.
这就是踩石行动?
Was this Treadstone?
你在直截了当地提问?
You're asking me a direct question?
是
Yes.
我还以为你不会这么做
I thought you were never gonna do that.
出什么事了?
What happened?
我们与我们的人失去了联系
Well, we lost the communication with our man.
这几乎是两周前的事
This was almost two weeks ago.
我们整个小组没日没夜一直在干
We've worked around the clock.
我们睡在那儿 想方设法
We've been sleeping down there. We're doing everything we can.
- 但你不想让我知道这事? - 你以前从不想知道
- And you don't let me know this? - You never wanted to before.
你以前从没失过手
You never made a mistake before.
瑞士苏黎世 戈曼萨银行
GEMEINSCHAFT BANK ZURICH SWITZERLAND
我能为你效劳吗?
What can I do for you?
我来办理保险箱帐户的事
Yes, I'm here about a numbered account.
你把帐号填在这里
If you just enter your account number here,
我就叫人帮你
I'll direct you to an appropriate officer.
美利坚合众国护照
PASSPORT United States of America
我叫杰森·伯恩
My name is Jason Bourne.
住在巴黎
I live in Paris.
我在想...
I'm trying to think...
离我上次来这里有多久了?
How long's it been since I was here last?
我不敢肯定
I'm not sure.
肯定有三星期了
It must be three weeks.
对 是巴黎
Yes, in Paris.
有没有杰森·伯恩的电话号码
Do you have the number for a Jason Bourne?
有的 先生 需要给你接通吗?
Yes. Would you lie me to connect you?
请接通
Yes, please.
这里是46990384
This is 46990384.
请在听到信号声后留言
Leave a message at the beep.
美国公民
U.S. Citizens
我是美国人
I'm an American.
好的
Okay.
站住
Hold it.
你们在这没有管辖权
You've no jurisdiction here.
站在外边 明白吗?
Hold it there. Okay?
不
No.
抱歉 这不是我现在住址 明白吗?
Excuse me. No. This is not my current address, oay?
它在我两天前开始排队时还是
This was my address until two days ago, when I started standing in line.
我现在已没有公寓了
Now I lose my apartment, okay?
这意味着没有住址 电话 钱 时间
That means no address, no phone, no money, no time.
- 而我还没拿到签证? - 库鲁茨小姐 请冷静
- And I still have no visa! - Miss Kreutz, please.
我必须请你放低声音
I must ask you to keep your voice down.
抱歉 但上周与我谈话的那家伙在哪?
Excuse me. But where's the guy that I talked to last week?
每周都换新人 凭什么要我...
Every week it's a new person. How am I supposed to...
我不知道你上周见的是谁
I don't know who you saw last week.
- 好 我帮你找 确信有他名字 - 请稍等
- Let me help you. I'm sure I have it. - Hang on.
你能听我说吗?
Could I have your attention for a moment?
这儿找到了 你看看
I have it right here. Just look at it.
你在费尽心思地躲避美国的移民法
You staged an effort to circumvent the immigration Iaws of the United States.
目前这是学生签证
This is a student visa now.
这已和绿卡无关 完全不是一回事了
It's not about a green card anymore. It's very different.
- 库鲁茨小姐 这不是菜单 你不... - 我把所有证明都带来了
- It's not a menu. You don't just.... - I brought all this proof.
疑犯...
Potential suspect....
是袭击案的同案犯
Help in assauIt incident.
红口袋! 拿红口袋那个人!
You! Red bag! The red bag!
站在原地不动! 举起手来!
Stop right there! Put your hands up!
我正赶过来
I'm on it.
快点! 快! 快!
Move it! Now! Now! Move!
一队从后面楼梯往上冲 二队...
Alpha Unit, tae the bac stairs and wor your way up. Bravo...
疏散方案
EVACUATION PLAN
上! 快上!
Move in! Move in!
好 没人!
Okay, clear!
疑犯是...
Suspect is...
二队正在上楼 即将到达二楼
Moving up staircase. Proceeding to second floor.
一队 你们可以上了
Alpha Unit, you're clear.
快! 快!
Move! Move!
一队 二队 目标也许有对讲机
All Units, target may have a radio.
用代码77 通话结束
Go to Code 77. Over.
代码77 收到
Code 77, copy.
趴在地板上!
The floor! Down!
没人!
Clear!
危险 请勿打开
DANGER DO NOT OPEN
请勿进入
DO NOT ENTER
快 往前挪
Go. Move up.
- 他现在在苏黎世? 现在? - 是的 刚收到消息
- He's in Zurich now? Right now? - Yes. It just came in.
- 他们确信是他吗? - 是的 他去了银行
- They're sure it's him? - Yes. He went to the bank.
是我们在银行的线人汇报的
Our source at the bank, that's who called.
快点
Come on.
他肯定会想到我们在监视银行 对吧?
But he's got to assume we're watching the bank, right?
我不知道 快开
I don't know. Come on.
我是说他清空保险箱却留下枪 是何意?
I mean, he cleaned out the box. He left a gun. What does that mean?
我说过 我不知道!
I said I don't know!
我更喜欢认为他已死
I Iiked it better when I thought he was dead.
你看什么呢?
What are you looking at?
我在里面听你说了
I heard you inside.
什么?
What?
我听到了你在领事馆说的话 我想我们或许可以相互帮忙
The consulate. I heard you talking. I thought maybe we could help each other.
怎么帮?
How's that?
你需要钱 我需要坐车离开这
You need money. I need a ride out of here.
谢谢你 我不提供租车业务
I'm not running a car service. Thank you.
我给你一万美元开车送我去巴黎
I'll give you $10, 000 to drive me to Paris.
什么 你以为我是傻子?
What, do you think I'm a fool?
你不干就是傻子
You'd be a fool not to take it.
- 这是开玩笑? 还是什么骗局? - 这不是骗局
- Is this a joke? Some kind of scam? - No, it's no scam.
到后我会另付你一万美元
I'll give you another $10, 000 when we arrive.
天啦
Jesus.
- 是抓你的吗? - 听好 你开车我付钱 就这么简单
- Is that for you? - Look. You drive, I pay. It's that simple.
我麻烦已够多的了 明白吗?
I got enough troubIe, okay?
明白
Okay.
我可以要回钱吗?
Can I have my money back?
好的 继续往下放
All right, go. Keep going.
继续
Go.
- 就这! 等等? - 不 应该是快结束的位置
- There! Wait! - No, it's got to be near the end.
弟兄们 我们撞大运了! 开始干吧!
Come on, folks! We caught a break here! Let's go!
我这有了
Okay, I'm up.
找到坐标了 飞机 火车 宾馆 医院
We're getting grids. Airline, train, hotels, hospitals.
谁查到了地址? 街道名? 戈门萨德
Who's getting the address? The street? Gemensheidt.
- 看好了 - 我找到了 我想我找到了
- Here we go. - I think I got it.
是他吗?
Is it him?
不是实时的
Unreal.
是38分钟前的镜头
This is 38 minutes ago.
苏黎世警方正搜查一个拿红口袋的美国人
Zurich police are looking for an American carrying a red bank bag.
他刚大闹了使馆 昨晚还把两名警察"送进"了医院
He just tore up the embassy and put two cops in the hospital last night.
把所有人都激活 马上 我要他们都行动起来
Get everybody up. Do it now. I want them all activated.
等等 激活所有人? 同时?
Wait. All of them? At the same time?
没错 我要伯恩在日落前躺在尸体袋里
You heard me. I want Bourne in a body bag by sundown.
好吧 在这贴张地图! 快点 弟兄们! 我们来安排好这些!
All right, let's get a map up here! Come on, folks! Let's work it!
口令:XX9897 待命外派特工
PASSWORD: XX9897 AVAILABLE AGENTS IN LOCATION
坐标正在更新
The grids are getting updated.
代号:教授 893489 黑猩猩已启动
CODE: PROFESSOR 893489CHIMP INITIATED
正在定位
LOCATING
位于:巴塞罗那
LOCATED: BARCELONA
登录已被接受 键入命令:回车
ENTRANCE ACCEPTED TYPE COMMAND: ENTER
连接中
CONNECTING
预备模式 准备投放武器
PREP MODE AND ARM READY FOR TRANSPORT
原地待命
HOLD PATTERN UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE
发送
SENDING
预备模式 武器已可随时投放
PREP MODE AND ARM READY FOR TRANSPORT
汉堡
HAMBURG
激活代号:曼海姆
ACTIVATION CODE: MANHEIM
预备模式 武器投放苏黎世
PREP MODE AND ARMlTRANSPORT ZURICH
智利护照 / 立即派发 432ZZ45
PASSPORT CHILElIMMEDIATE DISPATCH 432ZZ45
锁定目的地苏黎世 发送
HOLD DESTINATION ZURICH SENDING
地点:罗马
LOCATION: ROME
卡斯特
CASTEL
连接中 地点:意大利罗马 信号传送已确认
CONNECTING LOCATION: ROME ITALY TRANSMISSION CONFIRMED
地点:意大利罗马
LOCATION: ROME ITALY
这对我来说没什么 因为我已有准备
...which was fine with me because I was ready.
即便在阿姆斯特丹呆六个月也不确信...
After six months in Amsterdam, you're not sure...
是在那呆了20分钟还是20年 你知道我的意思吧
...if you've been there 20 minutes or years, you now.
因此我带着钱离开那 加入朋友一起...
So I went. I took all the money I had. I went in with friends...
接手了法国比亚里兹郊外的 一个很棒的冲浪商店
...we took over this really cool surf shop outside Biarritz,
它紧挨着海边
right by the water.
那简直太好了
It was amazing.
那三个月实在是太好了 直到后来发现...
It was just amazing for about three months, until it turned out that this...
把商店预租给我们的那个蠢蛋实际上骗了我们 而且...
...jerk who had fronted us the lease was actually shining everyone on and....
而且怎样?
And what?
"怎样"是什么意思? 你听好
What do you mean ''what''? Listen to me.
我一直不停地说了快60公里的路
I've been speed-talking for about 60 kilometers now.
我一紧张就要说...我说这些是因为我紧张
I talk when I'm nervous. I mean, I talk like this when I'm nervous.
- 我要闭嘴不说了 - 别那样
- I'm gonna shut up now. - No, don't do that.
我已有段时间没和人说话了
I haven't talked to anybody in a while.
对 但我们没有说话 就我在说
Yeah, but we're not talking. I'm talking.
自离开苏黎世后 你说了有十个字
You've said, like, 10 words since we left Zurich.
嗯 听你说是一种休息
Well, listening to you, it's relaxing.
我有一阵没睡觉了 而且...
I haven't slept in a while and....
而且还遇上这头疼的事
And I've had this headache.
就像在脑子里不停地运转...
It's like a constant thing in my head...
而且刚开始触及背景...
...and it's just starting to move to the background...
因此接着说吧
...so keep going.
真的 如果你愿意 就请便
Really, if you want, please keep talking.
好吧
Okay.
你喜欢什么样的音乐?
What kind of music do you like?
喜欢什么样的? 说啊
What do you like? Come on.
- 还是算了吧 - 不 告诉我
- You know what? Never mind. - No, it's fine. Tell me.
你想听什么?
What do you want to listen to?
我不知道
I don't know.
得了 这没什么好难的 你喜欢什么? 告诉我
Come on, it's not that hard. What do you like? Tell me.
不知道
I don't know.
谁会付两万美元坐车去巴黎?
Who pays $20, 000 for a ride to Paris?
见鬼
Fuck it.
两周前发生的事 我什么也记不起来了
I can't remember anything that happened before two weeks ago.
- 真幸运 - 不 我是说真的
- Lucky you. - No, I'm serious.
我不知道我是谁 我不知道我要去哪
I don't know who I am. I don't know where I'm going.
全不知道
None of it.
- 是吗? 像健忘症? - 对
- What? Like amnesia? - Yes.
- 健忘症 - 对
- Amnesia. - Yes.
好吧
Right.
- 这是观察该庭院的最好角度? - 是唯一角度
- And that's the best angle of the courtyard? - That's the only angle.
他们在这些街道或这一地区有什么?
What do they have of the streets? Or, you know, the area?
肯定有东西
They must have something.
等等
Hang on.
他在干嘛?
What is he doing?
玩游戏? 警告我们? 威胁我们?
Is it a game? Is he warning us? Is it a threat?
长官 看这里
Sir? Look at this.
- 这是哪? - 某个角度观察到的那条街
- What's that? - It's an angle of the street, a sort of alley.
增强信号
Just enhance it.
那个人是谁?
Now, who the hell is that?
玛丽·库鲁茨
Marie Helena Kreutz.
26岁 出生在汉诺威 她父亲是焊接工
She's 26, born outside Hanover. Her father was a welder.
死于87年
He died in '87.
还没她母亲的资料 她祖母仍住在汉诺威
We still don't have the mother. The grandmother, she's still in Hanover.
看来她成了这场家庭小灾难中的依靠
It looks like she's the anchor for this little domestic disaster.
还有个同母异父的弟弟
And there's a stepbrother.
麻烦的是 她是"吉普赛人"
It's tough. The girl's a gypsy.
我是指她四处出现 但充其量也就是乱跑而已
I mean, she pops up on the grid here and there, but it's chaotic at best.
95年时 她在西班牙付过电费
She paid some electric bilIs in Spain, '95.
96年在比利时 有三个月用自己的名字作户主安装过电话
Had a phone in her name for three months in Belgium, '96.
没有纳税和贷款记录
No taxes, no credit.
我不喜欢这人 我要你们深入调查她
I don't like her. I want to go deep.
查她祖母和那半个弟弟的电话记录
Get a phone log for Granny and the half-brother.
查与她有关的任何人
Anybody we can cross-file.
我要知道她过去六年都呆过哪些地方
I want to now every place she's slept in the past six years.
叫巴黎方面把这些印出来给外勤人员
Have Paris get these out in the field.
法国巴黎 踩石行动密点
TREADSTONE SAFE HOUSE PARIS, FRANCE
我没有编故事
I'm not maing this up.
这些是真的
These are real.
好吧
Okay.
谁的银行保险箱里会装满了...
Who has a safety deposit box full of...
钱 六本护照 还有一把枪?
...money and six passports and a gun?
谁会把银行帐号藏在屁股?
Who has a bank account number in their hip?
我进来后做的第一件事 就是全面观察...
I come in here, and the first thing I'm doing is I'm catching the sightlines...
寻找出口
...and looking for an exit.
我也看见出口标志了 但我不担心
I see the exit sign, too. I'm not worried.
我是说你遭枪击了
I mean, you were shot.
人在惊吓状态下会做出反常的事来
People do all inds of weird and amazing stuff when they are scared.
我可以告诉你...门外六辆车的牌号
I can tell you the license plate numbers of all six cars outside.
我可以告诉你...女服务员是左撇子...
I know that our waitress is left-handed...
还有坐在柜台边那小子重98公斤 他还没喝多
...and the guy sitting at the counter weighs 215 pounds and can handle himself.
我知道要想找枪的最佳地点...是那辆灰色卡车的驾驶室
I now the best place to loo for a gun is the cab of the gray truc outside.
在目前的海拔高度
At this altitude,
我可以全速跑上八百米而手不发抖
I can run flat out for a half-mile before my hands start shaking.
我为什么会知道这些?
Now why would I know that?
我怎能知道这些 却不知自己是谁?
How can I know that and not know who I am?
巴黎103 里尔350
PARIS 103 LILLE 350
嘿
Hey.
我睡着了
I slept.
- 简直不敢相信 - 你太困了
- I can't believe it. - Yeah, well, you were tired.
我一直没睡
I haven't slept.
啊 到了 为两万美元的缘故 我免费赠送早餐
Oh, here. For $20, 000, I like to throw in breakfast.
你停车加过油吗?
Did you stop for gas?
你睡得跟死猪一样
You were pretty out of it.
你认为这儿有家人在等着你?
So, do you think there's, Iike, a family waiting for you?
不知道
I don't know.
我想过这个
I've thought about it.
是这吗?
Is that it?
104号
104.
对 地址是这 别停 继续开车
Yeah, that's the address. No, keep going. Keep going.
- 好的 怎么走? - 左拐 停这边
- Okay. Where? - Just take a left. Pull in over here.
好的
Okay.
那么 是这里了?
So, this is it, right?
我猜是的
Yeah, I guess.
天啊 这里我一点也认不出来
God, I don't recognize any of this.
好了 我该走了
Okay. I should go.
杰森?
Jason?
哦 钱 没错
Oh, God. The money. Right.
对
Yeah.
给你
Here.
谢谢
Thank you. Okay.
谢谢你开车送我
Thanks for the ride.
随时恭候
Anytime.
你可以一块上去 或在这等我
Well, you could come up. I mean, or you can wait here.
- 我去查查 你在这等 - 哦...不用
- I can go check it out. But you could wait. - Oh, no, no.
你可以等
You could wait.
我在这等的话 你很可能会把我忘了
With you, you would probably just forget about me if I stayed here.
我怎么可能忘了你?
How could I forget about you?
你是我唯一认识的人
You're the only person I know.
那倒是真的
Yeah. That's true.
我猜你不在家
I guess you're not home.
伯恩先生 你回来了
Monsieur Bourne, there you are.
伯恩先生 我还在想...好久没见你了
Monsieur Bourne, I was wondering... I haven't seen you.
哦 我回来了
Uh, here I am.
我想我忘带钥匙了
I think I forgot my key.
有人吗?
Hello?
你确信这些全是你的?
Are you sure this is all yours?
我猜是
I guess.
这是我的厨房
This is my kitchen.
有线索吗?
Any clues?
我想我是干航运的
I think I'm in the shipping business.
那你开始回忆起来了?
So it's all coming back?
我可以用一下卫生间吗?
Do you mind if I use the bathroom?
请便
Sure.
好的
Okay.
喂? 喂?
Yeah. Hello? Hello?
先生 巴黎女王饭店 请问转哪个分机?
Yes, sir, Hotel Regina, Paris. How may I direct your call?
- 你们是在巴黎? - 是的 先生
- Yeah, you're in Paris? - Yes, sir.
我要找你们饭店的一位客人
I'm looking for a guest there.
他叫杰森·伯恩
A Jason Bourne.
- 请稍候 - 谢谢
- One moment, please. - Thank you.
先生 很抱歉 没有人以该名字入住
I'm afraid I have no one by that name registered.
好吧 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
等等! 别挂! 喂?
Wait! No, no. Are you there? Hello?
请讲
Sir?
能帮我查另外一个人名吗?
Can you check another name for me, please?
请稍等一下
Here, bear with me one second.
约翰·凯恩 凯旋的凯 请稍候
John Kane. Kane with a ''K.'' One moment, sir.
谢谢
Thank you.
你是找凯恩先生? 约翰·凯恩?
You call about Monsieur Kane? John Michael Kane?
没错
Yeah, that's right.
- 你是他的朋友? - 对
- You are a friend of his? - Yeah.
先生 我要告诉你个坏消息
I have some very bad news for you, sir.
很抱歉告诉你
I'm sorry to tell you this,
凯恩先生大约两周前去世了
but Monsieur Kane has passed away almost two weeks ago.
他发生了意外 是在高速公路上
There was an accident. On the motorway.
他显然当场就死了
Apparently, he was illed instantly.
真的很抱歉 告诉你这消息
Really, I'm terribly sorry to be the one to tell you this.
你知道吧 我们是在他们来收拾...他的东西时 得知此事的
When they came for his things, it was made nown for us, you see?
谁来的?
Who came?
他的兄弟
His brother.
他兄弟留下电话号码或联系方式了吗?
Did his brother leave a number or a way to get in touch with him?
我想没有
I think not.
很抱歉没有
No, I'm sorry.
杰森? 没有热水
Jason? There's no hot water.
水冰凉
It's freezing.
我去试试厨房里的水
I'll go try the water in the kitchen.
你要不就呆在卫生间? 我去看看能否把水放热
Why don't you just stay in the bathroom? I'll see if I can get it hot.
这里的水也冰凉
Yeah, it's really cold in here, too.
水还是凉的
The water is still cold.
对 厨房里的也是 尽管我已放水了
Yeah, it's cold in the kitchen, too. I got it running, though.
那...
So....
怎么啦?
What?
没事
Nothing.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
没事
Yeah.
怎么啦?
What is it?
出什么事了?
Something wrong?
杰森!
Jason!
把它打开 告诉我里面是什么
Open that. Tell me what's inside.
你是谁?
Who are you?
有武器 且危险
ARMED AND DANGEROUS
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
天啊
God.
快回答! 你是谁?
Answer me! Who are you?
- 他有我的照片? - 好了
- He's got my picture! - All right. Hang on.
- 是苏黎世 是昨天的? - 不要
- This is Zurich, yesterday! - Don't...
我不明白你从哪弄的?
I don't know. Where did you get this?
站住 你是怎么拿到照片的
Stay there. How did you get my picture?
你从哪弄来的?
Where did you get this from?
你怎么弄来我的...我的天!
How did you get my.... My God!
我来处理! 你呆在原地 呆在那!
I'll do this! You stay there. Stay there!
- 你的鞋在哪? 把鞋穿上 - 好的 好的
- Where are your shoes? Get your shoes. - Sure. Yeah, sure.
他跳下窗户了 为何会有人这样?
He went out the window. Why would someone do that?
我们不能呆这了 这不安全
We can't stay here. It's not safe.
我们可以逃出去 但必须马上走
I can get us out of here, but we got to go. We got to go right now.
喂 你可以留下
Okay, look, you can wait.
你可以留下等警察来 不会有事的
You can wait for the cops. It's okay.
你等他们来就是了 但我不能 我必须离开
You just wait for them to get here. But I can't. I got to go.
玛丽?
Marie?
别吭声
Quiet. Be quiet.
别看
Don't look.
请报代号
Code in.
阿尔法 37509
Alpha 37509.
喂
Yeah.
稍等
Hang on.
是伯恩 他去巴黎了 去了公寓
Bourne went to Paris, to the apartment.
- 抓到他了? 说 - 他杀了我们的人
- We got him? Tell me. - He killed our man.
- 什么? 在公寓里? - 对
- What? In the apartment? - Yeah.
- 你必须把这事摆平 - 不行 我没法摆平
- Well, you got to clean that up. - No, I can't clean it up.
- 尸体在街上 - 那又怎样?
- There's a body in the street. - So?
街上有警察 这是巴黎
There's police. This is Paris.
监听警方通讯 尽可能地截获信息
Put up the scanners. Get as much radio information as you can.
你呆在车里
Okay, you stay here.
我去找地方把钱存上 十分钟后回来
I'm gonna go find a place for this money. I'll be back in 10 minutes.
嘿 我告诉过你呆在车里
Hey, I told you to stay in the car.
我的天 我叫你呆在车里
Jesus Christ. I told you to stay in the car.
我去喝了点东西 我以为你不回来了
I needed a drink. I didn't think you would come back.
喂 你必须去报警
Look, you got to go to the cops.
马上去 赶在事情变得更糟以前去
Right now. You got to go before this gets any worse.
- 就我自己? - 不会有事的
- By myself? - It's gonna be okay.
你把我的护照带上 给警察看
You're gonna take my passport, okay? You show this to them.
你有那张照片 还有这两万美元
You have that picture, you have the $20, 000.
把所有事都告诉警察 他们会相信的
You tell them everything that happened. They'll believe you.
他们只能相信你
They have to believe you.
玛丽 你不能只是坐在这里 这不安全
Marie, you can't just sit here. It's not safe here.
安全? 这一切都起始于使馆里
Safe? This is from inside the embassy.
- 谁能干这些事? - 我不知道 - 从昨天起
- Who can do this? - I don't know. - This is from yesterday.
- 他们怎能知道我们在一起? - 我这么做 是为你好
- How can they know we're together? - I'm trying to do the right thing.
就这么回事
That's all. Right?
为我好? 你把我独自交给警察
How'll you make this right by sending me there alone?
怎么可能为我好?
You think I want you to go to the cops? That's good?
你想去 那好 你去我就得逃!
You want to go, fine. If you go, I run!
- 你去说清情况? - 我不清楚到底怎么回事
- You tell them what happened! - I don't know what happened!
我不知那家伙是谁 以及照片的来历
I don't know who this guy was or about that picture!
我都不知我是谁!
I don't know who I am!
我是...
Look, I'm....
你表现得就像是我要害你 我是怕做错
You think I'm trying to burn you. I'm trying to do the right thing.
没人能做对的事
Nobody does the right thing.
听好 我不能带着你逃亡 不能
Look, I can't run with you. I can't.
我们一起就得像这么生活 我得...
We run, I got to live like this. I got to....
我甚至不知道我在躲谁
I don't even know who I'm hiding from.
这帮人知道我是谁
These people know who I am.
我必须留在这里 我得查明真相
Yeah, I got to stay here. I got to figure this out.
那就查明真相
So figure it out.
你来开车?
You take care of this car?
什么意思?
What do you mean?
在来的路上 我觉得车胎有点没气
The tires feIt a little splashy on the way over here.
车开起来有点往右偏
It pulIs a little to the right.
这是最后的机会
Last chance, Marie.
嗯...
So....
- 什么? - 我们就要颠簸了
- What? - We got a bump coming up.
把头转开 把头转开
Turn your head away. Turn your head away.
我们永远不能回这车上来了
We can never come back to this car.
明白吗?
You understand?
好 我们要把它擦干净 我来抹去指纹 然后我们离开
Okay, we're gonna clean it out, and I'll wipe it down, and we walk away.
- 就这样 - 好的
- That's it. - Okay.
我要找个地方供我们休息 而且 我得理清头绪
Okay. And I'll find a place for us to rest. And I got to think.
你有帽子或头巾什么的吗?
Do you have a hat or a scarf or something?
- 盖住我的头发? - 对 直到换发型
- For my hair? - Yeah. Just until we can change it.
有 那当然
Yeah. Sure. Okay.
好的
Okay.
法国巴黎 霍芬曼陈尸所
HOFFENMEIn MORGUE PARlS, FRANCE
不是他
It's not him.
这人没中弹
This man was not shot.
有何消息?
What do you have?
翁博希去了陈尸所
Wombosi went to the morgue.
他看了尸体 他不信
He saw the body. He didn't buy it.
他在哪?
Where is he now?
我说过我人手不够
I told you, I'm not staffed for this.
他在哪? 翁博希现在在哪?
Where is he? Right now! Where's Wombosi?
刚离开陈尸所
They were leaving the morgue.
刚走
They just left.
长官 你看怎么办?
Sir, what do you want to do?
我要拿瓶子
I need to get the bottle.
嘿
Hey.
你已打扫了房间?
You already cleaned the room?
我把所有地方的指纹都擦去了
I wiped the whole place down for fingerprints.
我可以走动吗? 会留下脚印吗?
Can I walk around or is it gonna leave any footprints?
可以走 这没问题
You can walk around. It's no problem.
不过 我们要记住碰过哪些东西
But we'll just keep track of everything we touch.
离开房间时 不能留下任何痕迹 我想这样会更好
I think it's best if we leave a room, that we don't leave a trail.
为何? 我们去哪?
Why? Where are we going?
我要去约翰·凯恩住过的饭店
I need to go to the hotel where John Michael Kane stayed.
女王饭店
The Hotel Regina.
如果我就是他 那他们就会有入住记录
If I was him, then they're gonna have some records.
我们需要饭店的帐单
We need that hotel bill.
好的
Okay.
不过 这变得有点复杂了
It gets slightly complicated, though.
因为你已经死了
Because you're dead.
没错
Right.
- 先生 求你别这样 - 他们想打仗 我们就给他们仗打
- Sir, Please. - They want war, we'll make war.
他们想杀我 最好一上来就把我杀掉
If they want to kill me, they better kill me the first time.
他们最好把我杀死 最好在我睡觉时把我杀死
They better kill me dead. They better kill me when I'm in my sleep.
听我说 尼瓦纳 我们需要这些人
Listen to me. We need these people.
要找到能帮我们的人 本身就够难的
It's hard enough getting people that we know to help us.
我们要谨慎
We must be careful.
我们?
We?
不 是你
No, you.
你要把那混蛋小子的头给我带回来...
You need to bring me back that bastard kid's head...
放在这所房子前面 向他们展示我们从事的战争
...put it in front of this house, and show them the war we're fighting.
但那正好...
But that is precisely...
尼瓦纳!
Nykwana!
动身前 我们要核对一下表
We'll give the watch a reference check before we go.
好吧
Okay.
那个公用电话的号码是多少?
What's the pay phone number?
616-2468
616-2468.
出口呢?
Exits?
有三个
There's three.
后面是内部人员出口 側面出口通向布满店铺的街道...
Service at the back, side goes to the street past the shops...
前面的是最佳出口
...front is the best.
要是我认为我被人跟踪
If I think I'm being followed,
我出来时 就把包挎在右肩
I walk out with the bag over my right shoulder.
要是没出租车怎么办?
And if there's no taxi?
我就一直往前走 不要回头看 直到你和我联系
I keep on walking, don't look back until you make contact.
怎么了?
What?
我们真需要这样?
We need this, right?
那好
Okay.
我要离你远点
I need distances.
你走进去选个位置 要靠近大堂中央
You walk in, you pick a spot. Some midpoint in the lobby.
你要数清并记住走到那个位置的步数
Count your steps to that spot, and then remember that number.
因为我给你打电话后 你要赶快行动
Because after I call you, I can get you moving.
明白吗?
You understand?
你还要数人数
I also need a head count.
你走到柜台这段时间 弄清有多少人
How many people from when you walk in until you get to the desk.
那里有多少职员? 当然还有保安
How many hotel employees are there? And obviously security.
不过要认出他们 或许没那么容易
And it might not be that easy to see who they are.
我会给你打电话 你告诉我那的布局 我们就从那开始干
So I'll call you, you give me the layout, and we'll take it from there.
女王饭店
Hotel Regina.
请转大堂公用电话
Yes, the house phone in the lobby.
- 怎么了? - 我...
- What happened? - l...
- 出差错了? - 我拿到了记录
- Did something go wrong? - I've got the records.
前台那个小伙当时朝我微笑
He, this guy at the front desk was smiling at me.
因此想到所有那些麻烦
So I thought, you know, all this trouble,
也许直接找他会更容易一些
maybe it's easier to just ask for them.
- 你拿到了帐单? - 他给我复印了一份
- You have the bill? - He made me a photocopy.
你直接要的?
You just asked for it?
我说我是凯恩先生的私人助手
I said I was Mr. Kane's personal assistant.
想得真棒
Okay. That's good thinking.
- 长官 要我... - 不用
- Sir, can l... - No.
翁博希在他巴黎市中心的寓所被暗杀了
Wombosi was assassinated in his house in the middle of Paris.
是的 我们刚听说
Yeah, we just heard.
是伯恩干的 我们几乎可以断定是他
It's him. It's Bourne. We're almost positive.
他被分派了任务 但却失手了
He had an assignment. He failed.
显然 他觉得自己必须完成任务
He obviously feIt compelled to finish the task.
天啊
Jesus.
我们认为 他现在就会回来了
We think he'll come back in now.
我是说程序如此
I mean, it's routine.
这就像是行为软件
It's like behavioral software.
他会照章行事
He's following a protocol.
既然他已完成任务 我们认为 他就会回来了
Now that he's completed the mission, we think he'll come back in.
他们总是这样的
They always do.
何时回来?
When?
他回来报到还要多久?
How long till he checks in?
- 24小时 - 24小时?
- 24 hours. - 24?
对 通常要这么久
Yeah, it's usually something like that.
然后呢?
Then what?
我说过 我们会把这事摆平
I told you we'd clean this up.
会摆平的
It will be clean.
我知道你是家潜水用品店 不过 你们店在哪?
I understand you're a dive shop, but where are you located?
马赛?
Marseilles?
你们公司具体提供些什么产品?
What specifically does your company supply?
抱歉 先生 你说你叫什么名字?
I am sorry. What is your name, monsieur?
你在这呆了三小时 却没找到一个指纹?
You've been here for three hours and you still can't find a print?
- 什么事? - 巴黎警察找到车子了
- What? - Paris police found the vehicle.
你已拨通联合保安公司海事部...西蒙·罗林斯的办公室电话
You've reached Simon Rawlins at Alliance Security, Maritime Division.
我们在巴黎的办公时间是早八点至下午五点
Paris office hours are from 8.:00 a.m. to 5.:00 p.m.
我在巴黎找到一个线索
I got a lead in Paris.
有两个英国南安普敦的 其余都是马赛的
The rest were Marseilles, and two out in Southampton.
- 有巴黎的? 是谁? - 联合保安公司 西蒙·罗林斯
- Paris? It's what? - Alliance Security. Simon Rawlins.
是留言电话
I got a machine.
凯恩先生?
Mr. Kane?
凯恩先生!
Mr. Kane!
- 你好吗? - 我还可以 你呢?
- How are you? - I'm good. How are you?
凯恩先生 请进来 请坐
Mr. Kane. Come right in. Please have a seat.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看 这是帕尔默三层甲板游艇
So, this is the Palmer Johnson tri-deck.
我猜你还是想买同一艘船?
I'm assuming you're still in the market. It's still the same vessel?
对
Yes.
我就是凯恩
So I'm Kane.
我刚作为凯恩开了会
They... I had a meeting as Kane.
- 他们说... - 我的确是凯恩
- They said... - No. I'm definitely Kane.
我刚以凯恩身份见了个人 他也认为我是
I just had a meeting as Kane and he knew me as Kane.
所以我的确是伯恩 也的确是凯恩
So I'm definitely Bourne. I'm also just definitely Kane.
全跟船有关
It's all just boats.
我有设计图 摄像机和保安系统
I got blueprints and cameras and security systems.
我刚查到约翰·凯恩的尸体
I just found John Michael Kane's body.
在巴黎这里的陈尸所
In a morgue here in Paris.
但如果你是约翰·凯恩 那么那个尸体到底是谁?
But if you are John Michael Kane, whose body do they have?
- 再说一遍 什么名字? - 凯恩
- What was the name again? - Kane.
凯恩
Kane.
约翰·凯恩
John Michael Kane.
凯恩 是121号
Kane. It's number 121 .
我想看尸体
I want to see the body.
我老板可能会回来 不允许这样做
Our boss could come back. We are not supposed to do that.
拿去吧
Come on.
是这吗? 尸体去哪了?
Is this it? I mean, where is he?
我不知道
I don't know.
怎么了?
What's going on?
这家伙来看那个美国人 但尸体不见了
This guy has come to see the American. But the body has disappeared.
他兄弟他们昨晚来过了
They came yesterday evening...his brother.
他没有登记
He's not in the register.
你是谁? 怎么回事?
Who are you? What's going on?
- 这里面的尸体哪去了? - 我说过 昨晚有人来过了
- Where's the body that goes in here? - I said someone came last night.
他们把尸体弄哪去了?
I know. Where'd they take the body?
听着 这不是联欢会 明白吗?
Look, this is not a carnival, okay?
大家都打电话预约 按规章办事
PeopIe call, they make an appointment, follow the rules.
这里进出都要登记 这儿很严肃 这的工作很严肃
Everyone signs in and out. This is a serious place. Serious work.
不是说你什么时候想来就来!
It's not just to come in whenever you like!
说得对 我们进来时没有登记
You're right. We didn't sign in.
滚出去
Get the hell out of here.
- 很好 我马上就去登记 - 行了 快走
- Fine. I'm just gonna go sign in. - Okay, go.
是这个吗?
Is this it?
- 慢点 - 你不能动登记
- Slow down - You can't take the book. This is it?
没事的 这有铅笔 太好了
It's okay. There's a pencil in here. That's fine.
亲爱的 你干嘛不去外面等着? 就它了
Honey, why don't you go wait outside? Here it is.
我们不能...
We can't have... Okay.
杰森 刚才怎么回事? 你要找什么?
Jason, what just happened in there? What are you looking for?
尼瓦纳·翁博希
Nykwana Wombosi.
翁博希去陈尸所看过凯恩
Wombosi went to the morgue to visit Kane.
明白了?
See?
- 然后呢? - 听好 他也出现在联合保安的小册里
- So? - He's in the Alliance brochure.
同一人
Same guy.
他知道实情
This guy knows.
我法语很糟 我不能... 好象是说一艘船或...
My French sucks. I can't....It says something about a boat or....
我看不懂 报上说什么? 你看了 告诉我 怎么了?
I don't understand. What does it say? You read it. Tell me. What?
报上说 翁博希在被杀前三周告诉警方...
It says that 3 weeks before he was killed, Mr. Wombosi told police...
一名男子在距马赛八公里的海上
...that a man came onto his yacht,
爬上他的游艇...
five miles off the coast of Marseilles...
并企图暗杀他
...and tried to kill him.
报上说 他把那人赶下了船 并击中他后背两枪
It says that he chased the man off the boat and shot him twice in the back.
报上说我是名刺客
It says I'm an assassin.
停车
Stop the car.
但你说的是到...我们马上就到了
But no...you said Rue de l... we're almost there.
就停这 这就行
Just right here, this is good.
叫你停车
I said stop.
怎么了?
What's going on?
Well...what's going on?
你搞什么鬼?
What the hell are you doing?
- 走 快走 - 怎么...
- Go. Go. - What are...
钱给多了
You gave me too much.
- 我们暴露了 快走 - 暴露? 暴什么露?
- We're blown. Come on. - Blown? What is ''blown''?
先生 找你零钱
Monsieur...your change, your change.
先生 你不能停这 你必须离开
Sir, please...You can't stay here... You have to leave.
继续走 继续走
Keep walking.
你认为他们会在那干嘛? 在监视饭店
What do you think they're doing there? They're on to the hotel.
- 不会 你不知道 - 相信我 继续走
- No. You don't know that. - Trust me. Just keep walking.
你疯了? 你这是干嘛?
Are you crazy? What are you doing now?
杰森!
Jason!
这就是暴露
This is blown.
- 玛丽? - 走开
- Marie? - Get away.
- 玛丽 站住 - 离开我
- Stop right there. - Get away from me.
你想怎样? 杀我?
What are you gonna do? Kill me?
- 玛丽 - 下一步就杀我?
- Marie. - Is that next?
听着 镇静 镇静
Listen, stay calm. Stay calm.
不管我们做什么都要一起做
Whatever we do, we have to do it together.
- 我们必须... - 我们?
- We have to be... - We?
我们有过的唯一共同之处就是我们都不知道你是谁
The only thing we had in common was that neither of us knew who you were.
我们已熬过来了 听我说!
We've passed that now. Listen!
警方会找我们的 在大使馆拿到照片
The police'll find us. The people who took the picture in the embassy...
杀死翁博希的那帮人就要来追杀我们
...who killed Wombosi, they're gonna come here and kill us.
你也在为那帮人干
The people who you work for.
我会带你去你该去的任何地方 我会带你去 我会让你在那儿
I will take you wherever you need to go. I'll take you there. I'll leave you there.
你愿做什么就做什么 永远别再见我
You can do what you want. You never have to see me again.
但在这不行 我们留在这就死定了
But not here. If we stay here, we die.
老天 这些警察真是干得"太棒了"!
Boy, great police work! Really brilliant!
干嘛不在那挂幅标语 写上"别回来! "
Why don't they just hang out a banner that says, ''Don't come back! ''
我的天! 法语怎么说"监控"二字?
Jesus Christ! What is the French word for ''stakeout''?
这事发生在16分钟前
Okay, this was 16 minutes ago.
我们就从这开始
This is our starting point.
- 他们不能乘飞机火车 妮基? - 我在这
- Can't fly, trains are risky. Nicky? - Here.
我需要知道巴黎那些出色警察的一举一动
I need to know everything Paris's finest is doing on this.
遵命
I'm on it.
你说过24小时 但他并没回来
You said 24 hours, and he's not back.
但我们很清楚他现在在哪
No. But we got a good idea where he is.
你的这个秘密特工疯了
You've got a black ops agent who's off the reservation.
他把美国领事馆毁得一塌糊涂 如今又在欧洲四处逃命
He trashed an American consulate. He's on the run in Europe.
而你还不知原因何在 但我却面对监察
You don't know why. I got to stand before an oversight committee.
关于踩石行动 我对他们说什么?
What will I say about Treadstone?
你担心的是预算会议吧?
You're worried about a budget meeting?
我不负责此事 这事处理不好就难堪了
We don't take care of this, we don't make it to the men's room.
你现在明白了吧?
Now, is that clear enough for you?
我们会毁在这事上
We will burn for this.
我们两个都会的
We will both of us burn.
好 分两个组 达尔 雷继续监视电脑
All right, I want two teams. Daryl, Ray, stay on the grids.
布菜恩 哈里斯 史蒂夫...
Brian, Harris, Steve...
我要你们追查那个姑娘
...I want to work on this girl.
- 住宅图样进行得怎样? - 已开始做了
- And this residency pattern? - We started it.
做出来
Get it out.
参照了她祖母和她同父异母弟弟的号码
We cross-referenced numbers from the grandmother and the stepbrother.
我们发现有重合时 就提取号码...
When we found convergence, we took the numbers...
往回查
...back-checked them,
结合手头资料一起搜索 虽然线索有限
ran a search merge with other data we had, which wasn't much.
看这些图钉
Pins. These pins.
这些就是她过去六年住过的所有地方
These are all the places we think she's lived in the last six years.
一 二 三 四 五处
One, two, three, four, five.
这就是我们的资料库
That's our pool.
没人接听
No answer.
你让铃声响了几下?
How many times you let it ring?
- 你要不想去 我就搭便车 - 我说过送你
- Look, if you don't want to go, I'll hitch. - I said I'd take you.
这些就是目标
Those are the targets.
恳求 讨借 黑客 窃听 迂回 我不在乎你们用何种手段!
Beg, borrow, hack, tap, bypass! I don't care what you do!
我只要你们告诉我
I want to know everything you can tell me
这些地方发生的所有事
about what's going on at those locations.
你怎么知道这房子仍是他的?
How do you know he still owns this?
埃蒙总是有钱 他不会卖的
Eamon always had money. He would never sell this.
玛丽?
Marie?
干嘛?
What?
我们必须走
We got to go.
什么?
What?
我们必须走
We got to go.
我以为这儿会...
I thought it would....
- 见鬼 是埃蒙 我跟他说 - 我们走
- Shit, that's Eamon. I'll talk to him. - We're leaving.
埃蒙 意外吧
Eamon. Surprise.
是我 玛丽 哦 老天...
It's me, Marie. Wow, God...
来这真是对了
...there's a really good reason for this.
理由太充分了
There bloody well better be.
- 爸爸? - 等等
- Daddy! - Hang on. Hang on.
我没想到你会在这里
I had no idea you would be here.
我怎么会在这? 这是我唯一的房子 没错吧?
Well, why would I be here? It's only my bloody house, right?
是的
Yeah.
她带你来的?
Did she get you into this?
我们只准备呆一天
It was just gonna be for a day.
爸爸 阿兰要撒尿!
Daddy, Alain has to go pee!
好的 来吧 下车
All right, all right, come on. Here. Get out of the car.
好的 你进去
Okay, in you go.
过来 阿兰
Come on, Alain.
抱歉
I'm sorry. l....
我以为会没事的 但我想我错了
I thought it would be okay. But I guess I was wrong.
- 我要找妈妈 - 妈妈?
- Let's find Mommy. - Mommy?
妈妈在外面要呆两天 幸好这样
Mommy is away for two days, thank God.
你把自己缠上了
You've got yourseIf all tied up here.
好的
Okay.
他做什么的?
What's he do for a living?
以前做航运
He used to be in shipping.
他适合你吗?
Is he good for you?
你幸福吗?
Are you happy?
你知道我的 我在努力
You know me. I try too hard.
给你
Here you go.
睡个好觉
Sleep well.
晚安
Good night.
我睡地板
I'll sleep on the floor.
- 是几点的事情? - 早上11点45
- This was when? - 11:45 a.m.
完全在从巴黎开车所及的范围之内
Which is definitely within the driving range of Paris.
电话是从公路南側的路边休息店打的
The call came from a highway rest stop, southbound side.
嗯 这个黄图钉代表什么?
Yeah. What's this yellow pin?
她1997年在那里呆了几个月
She spent two months there in 1997.
距离最近的镇子是里奥姆
Closest town is Riom.
从她家的电话记录把国际电话整理出来了
We took her family's phone records and collated the international calls.
他们凌晨两点时在巴黎
They were in Paris at 2.:00 a.m.
他们无法乘飞机 火车也太危险
They can't fly. The train's too dangerous.
他太知道我们会去哪追捕他
He knows better than to go anywhere we might track him.
我们只能这样猜测
So this is our best guess.
- 你在这干嘛? - 看孩子 我担心睡不着
- What are you doing? - The kids. I was worried. I couldn't sleep.
你会弄醒他们的 我们得离开
You'll wake them up. We got to go.
我再也不想知道自己是谁了
I don't want to know who I am anymore.
我不在乎 我不想知道
I don't care. I don't want to know.
- 过来，我们谈一谈… - 我查明的任何事 我都想忘记
- Come on. We'll talk about... - Everything I find out I want to forget.
没事的
It's okay.
我不在乎我是谁 或干过什么
I don't care who I am or what I did.
没事的
It's okay.
我们有钱
We have this money.
可以藏起来
We can hide.
我们能这样做吗? 你有可能这样做吗?
Can we do that? Is there any chance you can do that?
我不知道
I don't know.
走吧
Come on.
乖狗 出来! 出来!
Here, boy! Here, boy!
早安
'Morning.
老天 你起得够早的
Christ. You were up early.
谢谢你煮的咖啡
Bless you for making coffee.
就一宿 你们没开玩笑
One night. You weren't kidding.
换换环境
For a change.
他也不在那
He's not there either.
- 车的旁边找了吗? - 到处都找不到他
- And you looked by the car? - He's not anywhere.
好吧 我们穿衣服吧
All right, let me get dressed.
- 谁? - 狗不见了
- Who? - Bloody dog's gone missing.
这事经常发生吗?
Does that happen a lot?
什么? 那狗? 早上不吃就跑? 从不会
What? That mutt? Miss his breakfast? Not a chance.
总是有原因的 对吧?
It's always something, right?
快去地下室
Get in the basement.
什么?
What?
- 快带他们进地下室 - 你在说些什么?
- Get everyone in the basement right now. - What are you talking about?
你和你家人有危险 我没时间解释
You're in danger. Your family's in danger. I don't have time to explain.
- 等等 究竟... - 埃蒙
- Wait a minute. What... - Eamon.
你们应该走
You should go.
- 你究竟干了什么? - 不是她 是我
- What have you done? - It's not her. It's me.
你们必须尽快下地下室去
You need to get out of sight and in the basement as quick as you can.
爸爸
Daddy.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们走
Let's go.
- 电话没声 - 知道
- The phone is dead. - Yeah.
杰森 外面是什么人? 是谁?
Jason, who's out there? Who is it?
你干什么?
What are you doing?
哦 不要
Oh, no.
我们根本不该来这 我...两个孩子...
We should never have come here. l.... These children....
不会有事的
That's not gonna happen.
在哪? 武器在哪?
Where is it? Where's the weapon?
还有谁在? 还有谁? 你们有几个人?
Who else is out here? Who else? How many you got with you?
我不会再问第二遍的
I'm not gonna ask you again.
我单干 和你一样
I work alone. Like you.
我们总是单干
We always work alone.
- 这话什么意思? - 你是哪儿的? 罗马?
- What do you mean? - Who are you? Rome?
还是巴黎?
Paris?
我们两个都参加踩石行动
Treadstone, both of us.
- 踩石? - 是哪的?
- Treadstone? - Which one?
巴黎 我住在巴黎
Paris. I live in Paris.
你头疼吧?
You get the headaches?
对
Yeah.
我头疼得厉害
I get such bad headaches.
知道晚上开车的感觉吧?
You know at night when you're driving a car?
也许和开前灯有关
Maybe it's the headlights.
踩石是什么东西?
What is Treadstone?
踩石行动意味着止疼药
Treadstone said pills.
他们叫我们去巴黎
They said go to Paris.
踩石在巴黎?
Is Treadstone in Paris?
瞧瞧现在
Look at this.
瞧瞧他们都让你付出了什么
Look at what they make you give.
好了 好了
All right, all right.
克劳迪娅 你坐前面并系上安全带
All right, Claudia, get in the front and put your beIt on.
好了 我把你放在后座
All right, we're gonna put you in the back.
克劳迪娅 坐前面去
AII right, get in the front, Claudia.
玛丽 我不再等了
I'm not waiting, Marie.
埃蒙 再等一等 不等了!
One minute, Eamon. I'm not waiting!
求你了!
Please!
拿着
Take it.
我取出了三万美金 其余都归你
I took out $30, 000. The rest is yours.
- 就这样? - 我就这些
- That's it? - That's all I got.
我不是这意思
No, that's not what I meant.
玛丽 不能再拖了 你必须现在就走 离开我
This is not gonna stop, Marie. You got to get out now. Away from me.
你必须离开 赶快逃
You got to get out. You got to start running.
你要隐藏行踪
You get low, you stay low.
不要再交朋友 要换新环境
No more friends. Nothing familiar.
这里的钱够你生活 什么生活都行
There's enough in there for you to make a life. Any life.
玛丽 我要走了!
I'm out of here, Marie!
嘿!
Hey!
快上车 你必须走
Get in the car. You got to go.
你打算怎么办?
What are you gonna do?
把它了结
I'll end it.
走吧
Go ahead.
求你了
Please.
请报代号
Code in, please.
报代号
Code in.
是哪位?
Who is this?
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
你派来的人已死了
The man you sent is dead.
所以不管你是谁 你最好开口说话
So whoever this is, you better start talking.
喂 杰森
Hello, Jason.
那你看现在怎么办?
So, what are we into now?
只有两个办法 要么回来处理好这事...
It only goes two ways. Either you come in and let us make this right...
要么只好继续玩下去 直到我们满意
...or we'll keep going until we're satisfied.
你是说 直到我死
You mean until you kill me.
不知道问题所在 我没法补救
I can't fix this if I don't know what the problem is.
告诉我怎么做 我会尽力而为的
Tell me what we're into, and I'll do the best I can.
杰森 你干嘛不和玛丽谈一谈
Why don't you talk to Marie, Jason?
- 问问玛丽她的想法是什么 - 说实话 我想她才不在乎呢
- Let's ask Marie what she wants. - I don't think she gives a shit.
她死了
She's dead.
真遗憾 是怎么回事?
I'm sorry to hear that. How did that happen?
她拖我后腿
She was sIowing me down.
- 杰森 我们做这些是...- 够了
- All we've been doing right from... - Enough.
够了
Enough.
今天下午五点半
5:30 p.m. Paris.
在巴黎新桥
Today. Pont Neuf.
就自己来 走到桥中间位置
Come alone, you walk to the middle of that bridge.
脱下外套 面朝东方
You take off your jacket. Face east.
- 我会再拨这个号码 - 等等!
- I'll redial this number. - Wait!
坐头班飞机去 告诉妮基我会在车上 给她打电话 叫她找"花边"
First flight out. Tell Nicky I'll call from the car. Tell her to find Picot.
快去
Go.
那好...
So....
我们打算怎么办?
What are we gonna do?
我说过我会把它摆平 我正在做
I told you I'dclean this up. That's what I'm doing.
你真能把他带回来?
Can you really bring him in?
这事我们不是已说过了吗?
I think we're past that, don't you?
你有什么高见?
Do you have a better idea?
除了从苏黎世到巴黎的一连串破坏...
You've given me nothing but a trail of collateral damage...
你什么都没干 换我来干肯定比这好
...from Zurich to Paris. I couldn't do much worse.
你干嘛不上楼去订一个会议室?
Why don't you go upstairs and book a conference room?
或许你能说得他俯首听命
Maybe you can talk him to death.
大巴 观光大巴 顶层
The bus, the tour bus, second level.
于目标无碍
Negative on the target.
- 一号位置? - 没问题
- Position one? - Negative.
- 二号位置 - 没问题
- Position two? - Negative.
三号位置 摩托车
Position three, motorcycle.
没问题
Negative.
杰森?
Jason?
我叫你独自来 我猜这对你太难办了
I told you to come alone. I guess that was too complicated.
那就试试这个吧:我走了
So try this: I'm gone.
操
Fuck.
接通妮基的电话
Get Nicky on the phone.
喂?
Yeah?
把房间清理好要多长时间?
How long to wipe down the room and move it?
- 处理掉所有资料? - 对
- Get rid of everything? - Yeah.
- 两到三个小时 - 那好 马上干
- Two to three hours. - All right, get started.
中间别停
Listen, no breaks.
两人守外面 一人在大厅 要警惕
Two men outside, one in the lobby. And keep your eyes open.
- 卡车留下? - 对 留下
- Keep the truck? - Keep the truck.
我要关掉这个小组 把设备搬到车上
I'm gonna close this unit down. We'll move the gear in the truck.
他们负责西班牙 马耳他和摩洛哥
They were covering Spain, Malta, Morocco.
对 当地警方的所有无线信号
Yes, all local police radio traffic.
不行 动北欧需要总部授权 好的
No, for northern Europe we need an authorized directive. Yeah.
好了 他们开始干了 我们半小时后收到卫星下传资料
Okay, they're on it. We'll have a satellite download in 30 minutes.
你的行动箱在哪?
Where's your field box?
- 你的行动箱在哪? - 就在那里
- Where's your field box? - It's right there.
整个系统出故障了
The whole system's gone haywire.
问题就在这边的这个窗户
That's this window right here.
餐厅窗户呢?
Dining room window?
我搞不懂
I don't get it.
没信号 电话没信号了
Dead. The phones are dead.
伯恩干的?
It's Bourne, isn't it?
别出声
Just quiet.
你动就死定了
You move, you die.
伯恩
Bourne.
枪扔了
Gun down.
进去
In there.
好吧 你想干...
Okay, so what do you want...
踩石
Treadstone.
你最好看看周围 没剩下什么了
You better take a look around. There's not much left.
- 你就是踩石? - 我是踩石? 我?
- Are you Treadstone? - Am I Treadstone? Me?
你说什么鬼话?
What the hell are you talking about?
他疯了
He's lost it.
你最好马上解释清楚!
You better start filling in the blanks here!
因为我还以为 我们是一边的呢
'Cause I thought we were on the same side.
哪边?
Whose side is that?
你知道自己都在干什么吗? 你什么都不明白!
You don't know what you're doing, do you? You don't have a goddamn clue!
我是谁?
Who am I?
你是美国政府的资产
You're U.S. government property!
你是身价三千万 但却出岔子的一件武器!
You're a malfunctioning $30 million weapon!
你十足是一个祸害!
You're a total goddamn catastrophe!
看在老天的份上 你就是杀我也得告诉我 究竟出什么事了
And, by God, if it kilIs me, you'll tell me how this happened.
- 你为何想要杀我? - 马赛那边出什么事了?
- Why are you trying to kill me? - What happened in Marseilles?
你派我去杀翁博希
You sent me to kill Wombosi.
杀翁博希? 没错 这事我们随时都能做
Kill Wombosi? Yeah, we can do that any time we want.
我可以派妮基去做这事 真见鬼
I can send Nicky to do that, for Christ's sake.
翁博希本该在三周前就死掉的
Mr. Wombosi was supposed to be dead three weeks ago.
他的死本该只有一种解释 那就是...
He was supposed to have died in a way that the only possible explanation was...
他是被自己的一名随从谋杀的
...that he'd been murdered by a member of his own entourage.
我不会派你去暗杀
I don't send you to kill.
我派你躲藏起来
I send you to be invisible.
我派你 是因为你这人根本就不存在
I send you because you don't exist.
我想知道在马赛出什么事了
I want to know what happened in Marseilles.
我不记得在马赛发生什么事了
I don't remember what happened in Marseilles.
瞎扯! 战士 这不可接受
Bullshit! This is unacceptable, soldier.
听见了吗? 你失手了!
You hear me? You failed!
不可接受? 你失手了!
Unacceptable? You failed!
- 你失手了 所以你要告诉我原因! - 我没法告诉你! 我记不起来了!
- You failed and you're gonna tell me why! - I can't tell you! I don't remember!
你激活了凯恩 你安排了与翁博希的见面
You brought Kane to life. You put together a meeting with Wombosi.
你找到了保安公司 你闯了进去!
You found the security company. You broke into the office!
见鬼 你挑选游艇作为下手地点!
For Christ's sake, you picked the yacht as the goddamn strike point!
你选了游艇
You picked the boat.
你选了日子 你跟踪船员
You picked the day. You tracked the crew.
食物 燃料!
The food, the fuel!
你把地点 时间告诉了我们
You told us where. You told us when.
你在那船上藏了五天
You hid out on that boat five days.
你参与了 杰森 你参与了!
You were in, Jason. You were in!
它结束了!
It was over!
对 你记得的
No, you do remember.
是吧?
Don't you?
我不想再干这个了
I don't want to do this anymore.
我想这不是你能决定的
I don't think that's a decision you can make.
杰森·伯恩死了 听见了吗?
Jason Bourne is dead. Do you hear me?
他两周前淹死了
He drowned two weeks ago.
你要告诉他们伯恩死了 明白吗?
You're gonna go tell them Bourne is dead. Understand?
你打算去哪?
Where are you gonna go?
我发誓 只要我觉得有人跟踪我
I swear, if I even feel somebody behind me,
我就会不顾一切地...
there is no measure to how fast...
把战火烧到你家门口
...and how hard I will bring this fight to your doorstep.
我现在是自己一边了
I'm on my own side now.
干掉了
It's done.
把它关掉
Shut it down.
踩石行动项目实际上已被终止
The Treadstone project has already been terminated.
本是想把它设计成一种高级行动方案
It was designed primarily as a sort of advanced game program.
希望能把它变成一个出色的训练平台
We'd hoped it might build into a good training platform.
说实话 对一项纯理论训练而言...
But quite honestly, for a strictly theoretical exercise...
这个代价也太高了
...the cost-benefit ratio was just too high.
该项目到此被全部取消
It's all but decommissioned at this point.
好了 下面是什么?
All right, what's next?
哦 这是...
Okay, this is...
黑荆棘项目
...Blackbriar.
黑荆棘是和国防部联合实施的通讯项目...
Blackbriar is a joint DOD communications program...
我们真的觉得该项目很有吸引力 它成功的可能性很大
...that we really feel has good traction to it. It's got legs. It'll run and run.
它融合了安全领域预防和反应的诸多因素...
It combines elements of proactive and reactive fields of security....
这是你的店?
This your store?
对
Yeah.
店不错 就是难找 但是...
It's nice. It's a little hard to find, but....
我可以租一辆摩托吗?
Think I could rent a scooter?
你有身份证吗?
You have ID?
算不上有
Not really.